Bruce Barbour Recordings
Bruce Barbour Recordings
1976-1980
Barbour, Bruce.
3.25 linear ft.
The Bruce Barbour Audio Recordings contain reel audio tapes from recitals, concerts and other performances.
4626989
Biographical History
Bruce Barbour (1923- ) is Coordinator of Performing Arts of the Munson Williams Proctor Arts Institute (MWPAI), located in Utica, New York in 1962. While in this position, Barbour worked on bringing films, music lectures, and recitals to the Museum of Art Auditorium. As a result from his involvement, the recordings in this collection are presumed to have been performances from MWPAI.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Bruce Barbour Recordings contains reel audio tapes from recitals, concerts and other performances hosted by Bruce Barbour, most likely at the Munson Williams Proctor Arts Institute.
Arrangement of the Collection
Recordings are arranged in chronological order.
Subject and Genre Headings
Music; New York State; Barbour, Bruce.; Music.; Music -- 20th century -- Performances.; Audiotapes.; Tape reels.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Researcher access to the recordings requires advance notice in order to produce a working copy.
Acquisition Information
There is no acquisition information regarding the Bruce Barbour Recordings.
Inventory
- Recordings
  - Barbour Lecture “Hoffmann”, 05/25/1976, 05/26/1976; barbour_001; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - “Ariadne”, 06/01/1976-06/02/1976; barbour_002; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - “Salome” (Richard Strauss), 06/08/1976; barbour_003; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - “Salome” (Richard Strauss), 06/09/1976; barbour_004; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - Benefit Concert for the Stanley Performing Arts Center in Utica, 09/22/1976; barbour_005; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - Ludwig and Wagner, 11/21/1976; barbour_006; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - Abduction from the Seraglio, 05/03/1977; barbour_007; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - Recital, 04/17/1977; barbour_008; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - “The Marriage of Figaro”, 05/12/1977; barbour_009; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - “Don Giovanni”, 05/17/1977; barbour_010; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - “Cosi fan tutte”, 05/24/1977; barbour_011; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - “The Magic Flute”, 05/31/1977; barbour_012; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - “Zarzuela” and “3-Cornered Hat”, 01/29/1978; barbour_013; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 1)
  - “Spanish Music”, 02/05/1978; barbour_014; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - “Joys of Chamber Music”, 05/11/1978; barbour_015; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - “Joys of Chamber Music”, 05/18/1978; barbour_016; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - “The Joys of Chamber Music”, 05/25/1978; barbour_017; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - “Diaghilev and the Ballets Russes/Stravinsky: Petrouchka”, 09/14/1978; barbour_018; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - “Stravinsky the Rite of Spring”, 09/21/1978; barbour_019; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - “Stravinsky, Apollo, Milhaud, le boeuf sur le toit”, 09/28/1978; barbour_020; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - “Milhaud: La Creation du Monde/Poulenc: Les Biches, 10/05/1978; barbour_021; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - “Satie: Parade/ De Falla - El Amor Brujo”, 10/12/1978; barbour_022; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - “Prokofiev: Romeo and Juliet”, 10/26/1978; barbour_023; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - “Hindemith: Saint Francis (Nobilissima Visione)/ Barber-Medea”, 11/02/1978; barbour_024; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - Schubert Memorial Concert, 11/19/1978; barbour_025; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - Schubert Memorial Concert Part II, 11/19/1978; barbour_026; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 2)
  - “Enigma Variations”, 03/26/1979; barbour_027; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - “Verdi: Biography”, 09/10/1979; barbour_028; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - “Macbeth”, 09/17/1979; barbour_029; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - “II Trovatore”, 09/25/1979; barbour_030; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - “Don Carlo”, 10/02/1979; barbour_031; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - “Falstaff” (Verdi), 10/08/1979; barbour_032; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - Recital, 11/27/1979; barbour_033; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - “Vienna: The World’s Music Center”, 04/21/1980; barbour_034; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - “Haydn and Mozart”, 04/28/1980; barbour_035; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - “Beethoven”, 05/08/1980; barbour_036; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - “Schubert, Strauss, Kalman”, 05/12/1980; barbour_037; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - “Beer-Garden, Ballroom, Parlor, and Cabaret”, 05/19/1980; barbour_038; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)
  - Barbour, 06/29/1980; barbour_039; 1/4 inch audio tape (Oversize 3)